Sandeep Chauhan

+91-6005030657

<u>Stackoverflow Github LinkedIn</u> <u>sandeepsajan0@gmail.com</u> <u>Moradabad, India</u>

Summary I'm a Software Developer with 2-3 years volunteer experience of application development. I have major experience with Python and Django. I love to work remotely with global developers. I always welcome of the new technology based projects. I have good problem solving skills. I am a quick learner and passionate about scaling the applications.

Experience

Intern at Spoonshot (Full-stack developer)

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Scaling and performance improvements of web crawlers implemented using Python/Django.
- Deployed a proxymanager for scraping framework on Django server with Redis.
- Dockerize the scraping framework and scale it with mongodb, celery workers and aws.
- Implement monitoring system with Grafana and influxdb.

Google Summer of Code Student

Apr 2018 - Aug 2018

- Python based implementation of <u>Hydra Client</u>.
- Implemented Hydra Client with the datastore Redis which also works as a cache for Hydrus.
- Developed a web app using flask for hydra-client demo.

Open Source Contribution

Hydra Ecosystem

- hydra-python-agent One of the main contributor who have built this project.
 Implemented Redis as a graph database using redisgraph and Cypher. Also created a Docker env., write tests, use designing patterns and etc.
- hydrus Add UUID in database and also add auto documentation using sphinx and fix some easy issues.
- hydra-astrodemo Created a demo for hydra-client using flask which also using the hydra-parser and hydrus server.
- http-apis.github.io Write documention for all the work done by me and also for some other projects related to my work.

Kivy

Fixed issue to integrate plyer with android as expected.

Projects

Go Web App

A Web app implemented with Golang using Redis as database having features routing, authentication, middleware, comments, error handling. It is a good reference for beginners because of its modules and good structure.

• Reactjs Projects

- Calculator
- o router-sample
- friends_passion(Beginner-friendly project to iterate over json data)
- ReactSwapi Api(React app to consume api and show data of swapi.co)

Friends

An anonymous web chat app implemented with Python, Django, Reactjs with database sqlite3 have some great functionalities like authentication, public and private groups(without showing users name), API's, messaging/posting, API's data presenting using Reactjs.

Social Networking

A blogpost web app which implemented using Python, Django and PostgreSQL as a database having features like authentication, manage profiling, blogs posting (with date and name). It is live or deployed on heroku.

Some small projects to become familiar with these technologies

- o Implement Redis with flask.
- Snake game based on pygame.
- Some simple apps based on kivy plyer.
- A simple kit-kat game using python.

Education

• Bachelor of Technology(2016-Present)

Shri Mata Vaishno Devi University, katra, India

Miscellaneous

- Student Coordinator at The CodeClub, SMVDU.
- Conduct and organize the various workshops, and programs like SFD.

Skills

Backend Development: Python(Django, Flask), Golang **Frontend Development:** React.js, HTML and CSS, JS **Databases:** PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Mongodb, sqlite

Operating System: Linux(ubuntu)

Other tools: Git, Bash, Docker, Celery, RabbitMQ, Grafana, influxdb, AWS